<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[R. Alex Anderson]]></title><description><![CDATA[It is what it is]]></description><link>https://ralexanderson.com</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2017 14:23:20 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ralexanderson.com/assets/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><copyright><![CDATA[2017 R. Alex Anderson]]></copyright><language><![CDATA[en]]></language><webMaster><![CDATA[R. Alex Anderson]]></webMaster><item><title><![CDATA[2016 Review]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p><img src="/assets/posts/2016-review.jpeg" alt="2016 Review"></p>
<p>Despite the intense disappointment many people have had in 2016, it’s been a good year for me. Here’s the highlights:</p>
<ul>
<li>After deciding to not take any classes in the Winter semester, I abruptly changed my mind. Good thing too — I took some of my favorite classes and was able to adequately prepare to apply for the Information Systems program.</li>
<li>One of those classes helped me discover a great love of printmaking.</li>
<li>I moved into a new apartment with some awesome roommates — musical roommates. After one of them encouraged me to pick up my trombone and jam, we ended up making a legit band, All of us at the Zoo. We’ve played a couple of gigs, competed in Battle of the Bands, and recorded a couple of tracks — its been a great thing so far!</li>
<li>I took a spontaneous trip down to San Diego for the wedding of two of my good friends.</li>
<li>I got called as the Second Counselor in the elders quorum for my ward, a difficult, trying calling simply because it’s hard to know what to do to help people. I just hope that I was able to make some difference.</li>
<li>I started doing website classes. I just taught people in my ward the basics of HTML and CSS, but it was still fun. Hopefully people learned something from me blabbing at them for an hour a week.</li>
<li>I started a new set of starship simulator controls, this time with several goals in mind: development momentum, so I could actually get them finished; collaboration with space center outsiders; and learning new and exciting technologies. It’s one of the most interesting and engaging projects that I’ve ever worked on and, while progress has been slow, it’s still progress.</li>
<li>I began dating someone who, at the beginning of the year I would have considered the most unlikely person. After an awesome three months, I proposed and she accepted. Crystal is the most amazing person, one which I feel incredibly blessed every day to have in my life. Choosing to marry her was one of the easiest decisions of my life. Without getting too sappy, she is patient, supportive, kind, thoughtful, and an inspiration to me.</li>
<li>I went to Disneyland twice! Once with my family and once with Crystal’s. Happiest Place on Earth!</li>
<li>I applied for the BYU Information Systems program. After months of waiting, I finally found out that I was rejected from the program. I was crushed, more so than I expected. Regardless, I prepared myself to change majors to Computer Science. Then, 5 days before the semester started, I received word that I was actually accepted. I was overjoyed. This is definitely one of the best things to happen to me this year.</li>
<li>Zach and I went to a Coldplay concert in Salt Lake. That was awesome! I’ve never been to a concert that big before, so I was blown away at the sheer spectacle of it. I loved every minute of it. A big thanks to Zach for hooking me up.</li>
<li>I got an internship lined up with Family Search! I’ll start in May. I’ll take a temporary leave from BlenderBottle while I’m there and hopefully pick it up again when the internship is over.</li>
<li>My mom got married. Kind of a big deal. Gary, her husband, is a great guy and he and his family fit into ours really well. It’s a great thing, in my opinion.</li>
<li>I went to see Rogue One dressed as Kylo Ren. No regrets. I also met Kylo Ren at Disneyland.</li>
<li>I became more of an adult with the purchase of a legit apartment, cable internet, and utilities in my name.</li>
</ul>
<p>Definitely the best part of my year has been Crystal. In an adorably cliché way, I never would have guessed that she would be my ‘the One’ when we first became friends, but more and more every day I learn why marrying her will be the best decision of my life.
On top of that, I’ve made some other good friends, created some good things, and hopefully made my corner of the world a better place.
For next year, I’ve got a short list of goals:</p>
<ul>
<li>Be the best husband ever and make the best Christ-centered home for my new family.</li>
<li>Keep playing with the band. Record a new album and play some more shows.</li>
<li>Get accepted to the Masters of Information Systems Management program.</li>
<li>Finish a full simulator set of controls.</li>
<li>Become more professionally proficient by working at Family Search.</li>
<li>Read more. Keep track of the books I read.</li>
<li>Write more. Keep this blog going, along with my technical blog on my personal site. Write in my journal every day.</li>
</ul>
<p>Here’s to a great 2017!
Cheers!</p>
]]></description><link>https://ralexanderson.com/posts/2016-review/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ralexanderson.com/posts/2016-review/</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Anderson]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 01:16:10 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Fishy]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/ralex93/blog/images/5GgbpWo2P6v2SDjLp-undefined" alt="Perky"></p>
<p>I&#39;m babysitting a fish. He&#39;s a beautiful red betta. I&#39;m not sure what his name is or even if he is a he, but for the sake of this blog post I&#39;ll call him Perky.</p>
<p>Perky leads a fairly ordinary life as far as fish goes. He wakes up, stretches his fins, filters his gills, and heads off to work. His job is swimming around his 1 ½ gallon tank, inspecting walls and checking to make sure there is enough oxygen in the water. That is to say, he just sits there and looks pretty. By fish standards, an exhaustive schedule.</p>
<p>But the highlight of Perky&#39;s day comes right around 9:15 every evening. I don&#39;t know if fish can cognate, but if this one could he would probably think something like: <em>Wow, what a day. I got a lot of swimming in. Hey look. Someone is coming to give me attention. He&#39;ll probably tap on my tank or something. Wait a second... is that the food jar...? <strong>IT IS!!!! OHBOYOHBOYOHBOYOHBOY OHBOYOHBOYOHBOYOHBOY OHBOYOHBOY</strong>...yum.</em></p>
<p>The fish seriously freaks out. He perks up (hence the name) immediately upon recognizing the food jar in my hand. He energetically swims around waiting for that moment when small flakes of plant byproduct land on the surface of the water for him to consume. What joy this fish must fill! What happiness! What fulfillment!</p>
<p>...and then he goes back to aimlessly swimming.</p>
<p>I&#39;m glad I&#39;m not a fish.</p>
<p>Cheers!</p>
]]></description><link>https://ralexanderson.com/posts/fishy/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ralexanderson.com/posts/fishy/</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Anderson]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 08 May 2016 03:50:45 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Feels]]></title><description><![CDATA[<iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/p2wdMwpYByI" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>

<p>I took a trip up to Logan a few weekends ago, which in and of itself was an interesting experience. I merely want to touch on one happening.</p>
<p>On my way back, I took a quick detour. Just after you exit the Sardine Canyon which leads from Brigham City to Logan, there is a small sign pointing down a solitary road. Mendon. It&#39;s a small town situated a couple of miles away from Logan proper. I haven&#39;t spent much time there, but it seems to me to be merely a residential town, with few businesses within the limits of the town. Houses, on the other hand, are all up and down the road as it winds around the curves of the foothills. These aren&#39;t suburban developments, though. Each home has plenty of room to breathe. It&#39;s a quiet, still place,</p>
<p>I&#39;ve only ever had one reason to visit Mendon. From time to time when my family would come up to Logan to visit my grandparents, we would stop by the Mendon cemetery so my dad could visit with his grandfather who is buried there. He would park, get out of the car and stand near the gravestone for a minute or two, pondering. Why we took these detours was beyond my childhood understanding.</p>
<p>I understand now. That&#39;s why this cemetery was where I headed.</p>
<p>The cemetery is picturesque - I truly have never seen a more ideal location for the dead to be remembered. It sits on a hill overlooking the entire Cache Valley. The developed landscape of Logan is clearly visible in the distance, but separating the two is a vast wall of fields and farms, protecting the scenery from the encroaching buildings.  Trees flank it on either side, providing shade and even more separation from the outside. The still of the town was perfect silence in the cemetery.</p>
<p>Whoever keeps the grounds is immaculate. The grass, though brown in. winter, was still handsome. This particular evening followed a rainy afternoon, causing the ground to be soft and moist as I stepped out of my car. </p>
<p>I approached the grave of my great-grandfather. Next to him was a plot of uncovered ground. There was no marker, but I knew who the plot belonged to. I was there just a few months before.</p>
<p>I stood there for a minute or two. I noticed some weeds in the plot and reached in to pull them out. Part of me immediately regretted that decision as the fresh mud smeared into my hands. The rest of me didn&#39;t care, and I dug on until the plot was cleared,</p>
<p>I stood for a minute more. Pondering. Considering. Thinking. I surprised myself with the emotions I was feeling. They weren&#39;t so much sadness as whatever the feeling for missing someone this point, I&#39;ve been an emotional stoic, without the slightest hint of negative feeling showing through. </p>
<p>But not now. Now, I was giving myself a chance to feel all the feels. Feels which I had denied myself for one reason or other - I had work to do; I had class to study for; I had other more pressing things at hand. But here, in the quiet stillness of the cemetery with the pastoral vistas surrounding me, with no care for time or appointments or deadlines or meetings, here I no longer had any excuse not to feel all the feels. </p>
<p>It came over me slowly. But I felt it. Numbness became tenderness, a sort of lonely sadness mixed with hope and love. </p>
<hr>
<p>One of the last things my dad did before he stopped working for the Church was test the Easter website for mormon.org. He was proud of his work - it was meaningful work which reached far beyond himself to help other people realize the reality of Jesus Christ, not only as a person, but as a Savior.</p>
<p>How fitting - Easter. Resurrection day.</p>
<p>It&#39;s something which I&#39;ve always taken for granted as a member of the Church, but others might not have the same hope: resurrection is real. Christ did in reality literally resurrect. It&#39;s not just a figurative, spiritual resurrection. He was alive again. Which means everyone else will be alive again too. </p>
<p>I&#39;ll see my dad again.</p>
]]></description><link>https://ralexanderson.com/posts/the-feels/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ralexanderson.com/posts/the-feels/</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Anderson]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2016 18:50:55 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Choice]]></title><description><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>The greater the agency, the greater the growth</p>
</blockquote>
<p>At a recent Stake Conference, one of the general authorities said this, almost in passing. It was a simple one-liner, but you could tell that it was something which this man had either learned or was in the process of learning.</p>
<p>The more agency you put into an activity, the greater you will grow.</p>
<p>In most cases, growth is the product of struggle. Muscles burn with fatigue before they strengthen; exhaustive studies lead to greater knowledge; and sometimes, it takes going well out of your comfort zone to be included in a social circle.</p>
<p>But this thought challenges that idea slightly. Not only must you struggle to grow, but to receive the greatest gains, you have to want to do it. You doing the activity cannot be at the pleading of others; you must motivate from within.</p>
<p>I recall my weight training class. there were the people that had a rhythm and were obviously pushing themselves to the point that their sweat was measured in buckets. There were also those who would spend a significant amount of time at the drinking fountain or fiddling with the settings on the machines instead of moving metal. I wouldn&#39;t be surprised if those individuals got different results.</p>
<p>It&#39;s like the difference between people who learn for learnings sake and those who just want a grade. There is a professor at BYU who is not only a notoriously instructor, but also has a reputation for teaching an exceptionally difficult course. Getting a B in his class is considered excellent. Fortunately, for those who care only about grades, there are a few other professors teaching the class.</p>
<p>I took his class and found out firsthand that all of that is true. I learned a lot, but it was a challenge. I studied more and harder than I did for any class before, but I wanted to do it that way. I knew what I was getting myself into. It was my choice, so I owned it. In the end, I did excellently in that class. (see above) As such, that class totally shifted my world-view and provided me with a new way to understand everything.</p>
<p>Conversely, there was once a family I taught on my mission who would reluctantly do the things we as missionaries would ask them to do. We would badger them, pester them, hound them, untiil finally they would come to church or say a prayer or read their scriptures.</p>
<p>So, yes. We were good missionaries. We got the investigators to do the thing. But to what end? Did they experience real growth? Was I really fulfilling my duty as a missionary? This could have been one of those circumstances where not doing anything would be the best thing I could have done. Instead, I had them sacrifice their potential for growth by minimizing their agency.</p>
<p>So what&#39;s the takeaway?</p>
<ul>
<li><p>Take ownership. If you aren&#39;t going to invest yourself fully into what you are doing, why do it? May I be so bold to say that I bet you could find something better to do. Follow the &quot;No, Yes, Heck yes&quot; pattern for all big choice you have to make. If it&#39;s a no, don&#39;t do it. If it&#39;s a yes, avoid doing it - you won&#39;t be as invested. If it&#39;s a Heck Yes, go for it! (ps. I may be so bold. It&#39;s my blog. I&#39;ll write what I want)</p>
</li>
<li><p>Okay, what if you aren&#39;t really feeling it, but you still have to do the thing. You&#39;ve committed yourself. Well then, figure out a way to make it a bigger deal for you. Make yourself want to do the thing. This can be tricky, but it makes all the difference.</p>
</li>
<li><p>Don&#39;t impose your agency upon someone else. I recently learned that Queen Elizabeth I was so incredibly popular and powerful because she provided more flexibility to her subjects than her predecessors. Her relinquishing of coercion and control ultimately gave her more power and influence. When you do the same for others, they will thank you for it. </p>
</li>
<li><p>Let people live their lives. Humbly live your own life the best you can and try to make a difference for those around you. Be a friend. Be trustable. Be the kind of person that other people look up to and want to be like. That won&#39;t stop people&#39;s poor decisions from making you sad, but if you push back against those decisions which others make, they&#39;ll push away from you. Influence comes from love and trust. That is what should be cultivated.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p>Cheers!</p>
]]></description><link>https://ralexanderson.com/posts/the-choice/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ralexanderson.com/posts/the-choice/</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Anderson]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2016 21:05:53 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Shank You]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>I first got The idea for Shank You at a company activity. One of the managers was talking about how his ward had put together a game of Assassin for his ward, and it was going really well. He mentioned that he was operating as the dispatcher, giving the participants their next target when one target was killed. In that role, though, he couldn&#39;t be a participant. To me, that sounds like an opportunity.</p>
<p>To start, I sketched out what needed to happen:</p>
<ul>
<li><p>Users needed to have a real identity. I could force Facebook logins so users had to represent themselves accurately.</p>
</li>
<li><p>I wanted to make this as big as possible, so there needed to be support for multiple games. </p>
</li>
<li><p>I also needed a human readable way to represent those games. I opted for a randomly generated four-word &#39;secret code&#39; which players could use join games. Later on, I also included a url scheme so users could join games by following a link.</p>
</li>
<li><p>There needed to be a time period for players to join games, so a start time was added.</p>
</li>
<li><p>Once the game starts, players should be assigned targets from their game in a circular fashion, so each person has one target and there can only be one winner.</p>
</li>
<li><p>Players need a way to show that they have been eliminated. I started with another four-word secret code which the assassin would type in, but a simple &#39;Surrender&#39; button proved simpler and more effective.</p>
</li>
<li><p>The game needed to recognize when the game was over and who the winner is.</p>
</li>
</ul>
]]></description><link>https://ralexanderson.com/posts/shank-you/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ralexanderson.com/posts/shank-you/</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Anderson]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2016 16:56:30 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[New Year, New Blog]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Hey Everybody!</p>
<p>I&#39;ve revamped my blog, which hopefully means I&#39;ll be writing in here a little bit more. I also think that I&#39;ll be writing about more technical things in addition to my spiritual and self-improvement themed posts.</p>
<p>If you have any comments about the blog itself or about what I should write about, feel free to get in touch (you have about three or four different methods on the home page).</p>
<p>Cheers!</p>
]]></description><link>https://ralexanderson.com/posts/new-year-new-blog/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ralexanderson.com/posts/new-year-new-blog/</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Anderson]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2016 05:53:33 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Two Zero One Six]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>After another spin around the sun, tis time for another yearly recap.</p>
<p>This year has certainly been harder than most in the hardest way possible - emotionally. I would say last year was the mentally strenuous year and the year before that was the physically strenuous year. This year was emotionally difficult. But, as the clichè goes, it&#39;s just like exercise - it only makes you stronger. I can say that. So, without further ado, here&#39;s the 2015 play-by-play.</p>
<ul>
<li>My brother and I landed our first client gig for our business. In exchange for two-way tickets to Europe (we didn&#39;t end up going, but it&#39;s all good), we built a homepage and registration website for the Royal Business Academy in the Czech Republic. It was a great experience and taught me a lot about freelance work (which one thing I&#39;m considering for a career) </li>
<li>I settled firmly into Information Systems as a major, with a Visual Arts (Graphic Design) minor. Other than Spring and Summer, I&#39;ve been doing school full-time.</li>
<li>I&#39;ve also continued my work at BlenderBottle. This job has given me so many opportunities to learn new skills. This year was my first foray into mobile app development after making a few internal apps for BlenderBottle. I&#39;ve taken those skills home and made some apps for personal projects. </li>
<li>In fact, keep a look out for the official launch of <a href="http://shankyou.me">ShankYou.me</a>, my new assassin game app.</li>
<li>I&#39;ve stayed involved with the Space Center and the Farpoint Creative team. I developed the <a href="http://farpointstation.org/">Farpoint Station</a> website last January for the cadets to log on to to get information about the Voyager club.</li>
<li>I also programmed and ran the <a href="http://spaceedventures.org/">Project Voyager fundraiser</a> website to collect money for the clubs and specialized rooms in the new Voyager Simulator. Also, look out for the new SpaceEdventures.org which will be launching when the Voyager is finished - that&#39;s some of my work too.</li>
<li>After construction began on the Voyager II in May, I was over at Renaissance Academy overseeing the work that was being done. Brent and I spent Memorial Day weekend with our other brother, Stephen, Brent&#39;s (then) girlfriend, and her dad running cable through the entire ship. Many of my weekends have been spent wiring up speakers or placing light fixtures. It&#39;s hard to guess, but I would estimate that over the course of this entire year I&#39;ve spent at least 500 hours working on that space ship. </li>
<li>On August 1st at noon, after years of fighting it, my father succumbed to cancer and passed away. This has been a pivotal part of my year - everything before it and after it has pretty much revolved around this moment. There was the buildup and anxiety and uncertainty that surrounded the situation as he grew weaker and weaker over the year. Then the funeral. Then adjusting to life after. It&#39;s still a challenge and I think about him every day. But this is the way things are supposed to be. Thanks again to everyone who has been supportive during this entire year. It means the world to me and my family.</li>
<li>I bought a car. Her name is Sunny and she&#39;s wonderful.</li>
<li>I went with Brent to Los Angeles for a day. We played at the beach, went to Disneyland, and just partied. Why did we go? Just for kicks, but it also served as the bachelor party, because...</li>
<li>Brent got married! Finally! This turned out to be both a wonderful thing and another difficult thing. He&#39;s most certainly one of the happiest people that I know, but It&#39;s been tough adjusting to this change in the relationship I have with my brother. </li>
<li>I went to ComicCon SLC for the first time. It wasn&#39;t exactly what I was expecting, but it was still fun. Worth going to at least once.</li>
<li>I went on a cruise! And finally left the country! My mom, sister and I went down to Ensenada, Mexico for a mid-semester vacation. It was great fun, and certainly an experience.</li>
<li>I discovered my love of live music. That is to say I went to four or five concerts last year. Good times.</li>
<li>Pretty much the rest of 2015 was spent doing the expected - school, work, and Spaceship. Those three things have defined my life for the past 12 months.</li>
</ul>
<p>I&#39;ve come to learn a lot about myself over the year. It&#39;s been tough, but it&#39;s been good. So, here&#39;s to 2016 - a year of change and challenge, a year of learning and love, a year of growth and... er... giving? gratitude? I&#39;m sorry, my eloquence failed me there. Yeah, we&#39;ll go with gratitude.</p>
<p>2016 - a year of Gratitude™</p>
<p>Whatever. Have a great year everybody!</p>
<p>Cheers!</p>
]]></description><link>https://ralexanderson.com/posts/two-zero-one-six/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ralexanderson.com/posts/two-zero-one-six/</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Anderson]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 05:28:27 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Becoming]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>read an article from a guy named Mark Manson - a pretty sharp life coach (but a pretty profane dude - watch out if you ever read his stuff). <a href="http://markmanson.net/be-patient">This one in particular</a> was about the Titanic (but you could put just about any massive object in it&#39;s place - it&#39;s all <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Newton%27s_laws_of_motion#Newton.27s_first_law">the same principle</a>). Being a large, heavy ship, she was fairly inept at making quick changes to her course, which is the main reason she wasn&#39;t able to avoid the ice berg after seeing it. She only had a single rudder and a couple of propellors to set its course with. She didn&#39;t have port and starboard thrusters like modern maritime vessels do (and even then, it probably wouldn&#39;t have helped her much anyway). </p>
<p>The point of all that, other than to provide a pretty powerful image, was to compare people to ships (we already do the same thing the other way around). And I&#39;ve seen it over and over again in my life and in the lives of others - we just want to stick to the status quo and avoid deviation. </p>
<p>Interestingly enough, that&#39;s not to say that we want to avoid a change of scene. In fact, I knew a guy who couldn&#39;t stand to live in one place for a substantial period of time. Even well into his &#39;settle down and raise a family&#39; years, he would pack the whole clan up and move halfway across the country. And that&#39;s just it - that is the lifestyle he was used to.</p>
<p>Chances are, these behaviors and tendencies started when we were younger - perhaps these things we do are because that&#39;s just what the family always did. But ultimately, these behaviors are simply because of repeated exposure over long periods of time - setting the course of our lives one moment at a time.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>This is to be human. We all have this great inner psychological inertia in us....
This is because our minds are essentially accumulations of habits. We all have physical habits, like brushing your teeth every day or flossing the cat. But we also have mental habits — biases and stereotypes we regularly fall back upon, worn and weathered explanations for the world’s difficulties, assumptions that get us out of a psychological pickle. You get the point. We rely on these mental habits just as we rely on physical habits — they sort and rearrange the world for us without having to expend any conscious effort.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>I wish I had a source for this fact, but alas, I do not. However, at very least as hearsay, the human brain is designed in the most fascinating of ways. As neurons fire and electrical and chemical impulses travel between the synapses, those connections become stronger. That is, the more you think something, the easier it is to think, or rather, the harder it is to un-think. This is why muscle memory works, why you can remember a phone number from 20 years ago (before we had cellphones, so you memorized it of necessity) - because these patterns were embedded into the cerebral cortex over hundreds, if not thousands of firings. </p>
<p>While both of those thought-patterns were probably created on purpose, the patterns which affect us the most are the ones we create day after day, moment after moment, as we go through life living, acting, thinking in certain ways, determined by our lifestyle and life situation. Diverting from that becomes especially challenging simply because the way we&#39;ve always thought and always lived is the path of least resistance for our neural signals.</p>
<p>So, when we do divert our course, wether it be moving out for the first time, a new job, losing your job, getting married, losing a spouse, etc. it takes us a while to adjust to the change, to divert our mental course to a path most conducive to the current life situation.</p>
<p>One example: There is a friend of mine (she&#39;ll forgive me for sharing this story) who recently found new employment. It&#39;s been a little frustrating for her. In her job, she just can&#39;t seem to get over the feeling that she isn&#39;t performing as well and as quickly as she needs to. As she puts it &quot;I&#39;m too slow.&quot;</p>
<p>And I want to say &quot;Of course you are! You&#39;re just getting started!&quot; And after writing this post, I might add &quot;Your brain is still working on putting together the synaptic connections necessary to perform these tasks quickly and efficiently.&quot; And I would finish with &quot;Go easy on yourself. Is anyone else getting on your case? No? Then there&#39;s no problem.&quot; </p>
<p>That&#39;s why it&#39;s great to remember that we probably aren&#39;t all human beings - we&#39;re human becomings - striving to achieve something that we aren&#39;t - yet.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Life transitions, even when good, are always difficult, and they are always slow and gradual. There have been times where I have felt lost, like I was no longer the same person I once was, but also unsure of the person I was becoming. There have been times where I felt conflicted and confused, where I mourned for a past self that I knew I would never see again while anxiously awaiting a future self who seemingly would never come. Old habits, both good and bad, have fallen by the wayside while I’ve picked up both good and bad habits to fill their space.
This is my steamship, slowly, mechanically turning itself, veering onto a new horizon, an unfamiliar yet calming trajectory.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>A few takeaways:</p>
<ul>
<li><p>As the article states, you have to be patient. Change of this nature take a lot of time (<a href="http://pmd.cdn.turner.com/tcm/big/tcmweb/FILMCLIPS/2011/01/hopscotch_haveanysausage_FC_235a_24f_mobile-baseline.mp4">and oxygen</a>), which there really is no substitute for. But it is possible</p>
</li>
<li><p>If our mental thoughts (and emotional responses, for that matter) can create habits, then we need to be especially careful about what we think. </p>
</li>
<li><p>On the other hand, bad habits can be broken. Again, this process requires time and effort, but it is doable.</p>
</li>
<li><p>Flexibility means being able to adjust your mental habits quickly. I don&#39;t know exactly how this is possible, but I do know people that can fit into any role or situation with little preparation and perform amazingly well.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>And this is life. This is part of the bargain. The universe says, “Hey, guess what? You get to exist!” And we say, “Hot Dang! That’s great!” not realizing that existence is, by definition, a merciless and unending foray into the unknown...
A good life is not a life without problems. A good life is a life with good problems. And so it’s despite the turbulence of the rocky waves and twisting tides, I can sometimes stare into the heart of my confusion and the crossed strains of joy and sadness, and smile and be grateful that it’s all there.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Cheers!</p>
]]></description><link>https://ralexanderson.com/posts/becoming/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ralexanderson.com/posts/becoming/</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Anderson]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 27 Dec 2015 05:25:32 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[This is what happens when I don't blog for too long]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Over the past few months, I&#39;ve compiled together a collection of totally unrelated yet meaningful ideas which I was planning on writing in this blog about, things which at various times have had some kind of special meaning to me, but just haven&#39;t gotten around to developing those ideas. Instead of leaving them to languish forever, I&#39;ve decided to just throw them together in one post in no particular order. Here it goes!</p>
<hr>
<p>This came from the comment section of a developer website which I visit frequently. I found it incredibly powerful and especially meaningful to those who are just getting started in anything. <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=2263085">Here&#39;s the source.</a></p>
<p>I guarantee you that everyone you know who you think is so much smarter than you got that way not through inherent ability, but through work. You might have heard stories about how incompetent they were in the beginning, but I bet you discount them and say &quot;well, of course they&#39;re not serious about that, this is just false modesty.&quot; No, it is really true.</p>
<p>Everyone I know who is really good started out that way. In fact I&#39;m starting to think that one of the prime qualities needed to become a good hacker is a kind of willful disregard of one&#39;s own incompetence, coupled with a strong desire to do something that&#39;s personally meaningful. In other words, you need hubris.</p>
<p>As long as you keep measuring yourself by stuff that&#39;s personally meaningful, you&#39;ll advance in your hacking skills -- don&#39;t worry about that. If you think you need skills before you start something personally meaningful, you will never, ever get anywhere.</p>
<hr>
<p>Much of life does not change, but let me testify to you that one area of life is good and will never change—that&#39;s when we live the principles of the gospel of Jesus Christ...</p>
<p>Your futures depend on the present. Live life well today. Life passes quickly. Let us not be guilty of hoping that someday we will become happy and contented, after college or after this next semester or after this next test or after this date tonight or after the bills are paid or after the kids are grown or when we are retired. The good will always outweigh the bad—let me say that again: The good will always outweigh the bad. There are far more lovely, fine, honest people in this world than those who are dishonest and injurious. May you learn at your age—and we at ours if we haven&#39;t—to recognize the good and to bring joy into the lives of others. </p>
<hr>
<p>  LUKE</p>
<p>But how am I to know the good side from the bad?</p>
<p>YODA</p>
<p>You will know. When you are calm, at peace. Passive. For my ally is the Force. And a powerful ally it is. Life creates it, makes it grow. Its energy surrounds us and binds us. Luminous beings are we, not this crude matter. You must feel the Force around you. Here, between you... me... the tree... the rock... everywhere! Yes, even between this land and that ship!</p>
<p>LUKE</p>
<p>I don&#39;t... I don&#39;t believe it!</p>
<p>YODA</p>
<p>That is why you fail.</p>
<hr>
<p>That was a memorable day to me, for it made great changes in me. But it is the same with any life. Imagine one selected day struck out of it, and think how different its course would have been. Pause you who read this, and think for a moment of the long chain of iron or gold, of thorns or flowers, that would never have bound you, but for the formation of the first link on one memorable day. ~Great Expectations</p>
<hr>
<p>Knowing what to do when no one’s there telling you what to do - that is what I call an adventure!</p>
<p>Cheers!</p>
]]></description><link>https://ralexanderson.com/posts/this-is-what-happens-when-i-dont-blog-for-too-long/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ralexanderson.com/posts/this-is-what-happens-when-i-dont-blog-for-too-long/</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Anderson]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 03 Oct 2015 02:43:07 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[How to Build A Space Ship Part 2 - The Plans]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p><a href="/posts/how-to-build-a-space-ship-part-1-the-background">Part 1</a>
Fair warning: What follows is going to be incredibly technical, especially towards the end. </p>
<p>I joined the Farpoint Creative team on accident almost. I was home from my mission for one short week before I got the itch to return to flying space ships. Even more surprising was my desire to program again - I didn&#39;t think it would be something I ever wanted to do again.</p>
<p>My brother had told me a lot about the new controls which he was building for this new simulator which was being constructed. He called his controls framework &#39;Flint&#39;, and it was designed to be a complete software solution to everything in a space simulator. The whole system was designed to be modular, allowing you to add or remove screens, stations, utilities, and functions as needed. It also meant that adding new functionality was as simple and making the one isolated package and including it with the rest of the system. </p>
<p>Flint is built on some cutting-edge software which was hardly even dreamed of when I had left on my mission, let alone being a reality. Now, all of the things which I had always wanted as a flight director were at my fingertips: Software controlled lighting, sound effects, audio, music, video, and other effects were now all possible; the ability to redistribute the entire simulator on the fly; controls which could be added to and improved over time, part by part; blazing-fast 3d animations. All of that is only the beginning. </p>
<p>And, of course, my beginning was a pretty far cry from all that. The first screen which I programmed for Flint was the Thrusters - a direct copy of the old Voyager&#39;s controls. You press a white button and you move in a specific direction; the yellow buttons rotate the ship. It took me a little while to actually program the screen. I had hardly touched Javascript (the language Flint is written in) before my mission, and the new framework had a bit of a learning curve. In the end, though, I had a completely functional thruster card.</p>
<p><img src="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/ralex93/blog/images/wtzpeDNKqoKrJZM6o-undefined" alt="A rudimentary screen"></p>
<p>This was just the beginning.</p>
<p>My work was eventually noticed by the rest of the team. I had begun tagging along to Space Center board meetings with Brent, my older brother, and during one meeting I showed off some of the things which I had developed. Vic invited me at that point become a full-fledged member of the creative team. </p>
<iframe width="800" height="450" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/7TYJyCCO8Dc?t=21s" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>

<p>Ever since the close of the original Space Center and Victor being brought on to Renaissance, the goal has always been to build a new simulator. This wouldn&#39;t be like the simulators of the past, though. It would be designed from the ground up for one main purpose: long duration missions. These serial missions would last months at a time, and focus on experimentation, experiences, and learning. </p>
<p>The simulator would also replace one of the computer labs, and as such would need to be usable and accessible during the day. All of the building code violations which closed the original Voyager simulator were taken into account, with specific consideration being given to accessibility for disabled students. </p>
<p>I remember some of the first creative meetings I went to were focused on architectural plans for the new simulator. Alex Debirk, a structural engineer and long-time flight director, had a few different versions of simulator plans, each with its own flair and style. His designs were limited by the space which was offered by the school and the number of students (26) which the room had to accomadate This only left a few options for placement of the bridge and control room areas. </p>
<p>Naturally, the best way to design a room is to case it out yourself.</p>
<p><img src="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/ralex93/blog/images/PfgHHZLaTjFdKHeTf-undefined" alt="Chairs help to layout the space">
<img src="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/ralex93/blog/images/nm4DuQCx2MbmnAfsW-undefined" alt="A first-attempt">
<img src="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/ralex93/blog/images/RGSGNo5NJwZ38KJnD-undefined" alt="Modeled using real dimensions">
<img src="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/ralex93/blog/images/KZJXmhqEETg6YTpMB-undefined" alt="Open space, with sickbay and engineering"></p>
<p>This was one of the original designs which was discussed. This particular design took advantage of the massive space left over from the room which the ship would occupy. It included a separate sickbay and engineering room just off of the bridge, had a small brig, converted the classroom on the far right side into a briefing and conference room, took advantage of the exterior door with a waiting area, and was filled with hallways; perfect for alien invasions. Several different configurations of the main bridge were considered. However, it was eventually deemed to difficult to build. It would have required massive construction costs including demolition of several walls and two entire rooms. </p>
<p>The objectives were changed to include leaving as much of the original construction as possible, with limited demolition. This drastically changed the designs, limiting what was capable in the space provided. However, Alex worked his magic and came up with this: </p>
<p><img src="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/ralex93/blog/images/T9nvxizZYHxCJiiBP-undefined" alt="The final concept"></p>
<p>This is the final layout which was decided on, incorporating many of the positive aspects of the original design: Sickbay and Engineering are separate rooms, now located on a separate deck accessible through &#39;turbolifts.&#39; The bridge has two separate possible entrances, allowing for multiple invasion vectors. The brig remained; the briefing room remained. The waiting area had to be nixed, but in exchange for that, a special, multi-purpose transition room was designed. Inspiration was drawn from subway cars. This &#39;transpod&#39; is meant to act as a space elevator, shuttle craft, and crew teleporter, essentially a &#39;room of requirement&#39; for getting the crew wherever they need to go. The hanging bars were an absolute must.</p>
<p><img src="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/ralex93/blog/images/nrrZ4NYKon7eEBxnd-undefined" alt="Subway car!"></p>
<p>The hallways were spiffed up with full-height bulkheads along either side. </p>
<p><img src="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/ralex93/blog/images/hPfEjMt6sKDFWyJTW-undefined" alt="A little too tall for as narrow as they are"></p>
<p>The bridge features curved front desks with two raised platforms on either side. Sadly, my picture omits the desk units. However, you can see the plans for a curved half-dome structure above the main portion of the bridge, which provides most of the lighting for the bridge through indirect light reflection. The captain&#39;s station is elevated, and in the far back is the Captain&#39;s Monitor (also not displayed). This is a table-top display which shows current tactical information, allows the captain to make plans, and features a multi-touch screen for drawing diagrams and interfacing with the computer.</p>
<p><img src="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/ralex93/blog/images/xKLpp2jZ4A9zmTqaB-undefined" alt="Oooh. Pretty"></p>
<p>The sickbay and engineering rooms are actually built into an existing storage room which is adjacent to the simulator, which adds both convenience and cost-savings. </p>
<p>An additional bonus is the inclusion of a &#39;Workpod&#39; room, a special storage space dedicated to a mobile transport pod which the crew will be able to use to repair and upgrade their ship.  </p>
<p>With the general plans in place, it was time to get to work on the more technical aspects of the ship. While every member of the team had invaluable contributions to every aspect of the simulator, I&#39;ll focus on the parts which Brent and I directly affected. </p>
<p>We took responsibility for anything which carried a low-voltage data signal, namely sound, computers, camera surveillance, video, effects, and lighting control. I&#39;ll touch on some of the decisions we made for each of these.</p>
<h2 id="sound">Sound</h2>
<p>This ship is one of the most unique as far as sound goes. Unlike any other ship, it has multiple zones which each need to be able to play different sounds at different times. In addition, there need to be microphones placed in each of these separate places to ensure that the staff can hear what is going on there.</p>
<p>The first challenge was figuring out a way of taking a certain number of inputs (such as music, sound effects, ambiance, and microphone input) and sending them to different outputs (such as the main bridge, the hallways, the briefing room, or the sickbay and engineering rooms). As it turns out, this isn&#39;t as easy as one would imagine.</p>
<p>Fortunately for us, a brand-spankin&#39;-new (read July 2014 new) digital audio deck hit the shelves, and it has all the features we could ever need. It takes all the inputs and outputs we could want and route them wherever we tell them, has an onboard DSP for equalizer and audio effects, and is completely computer controllable. That means that all of the audio can be manipulated through Flint. </p>
<p>Imagine for a moment that the communications officer is making an external call. Instead of a phone system, the comm officer will have a headset hooked into the sound system. They will talk with someone in the control room over that headset. However, the instant they transfer that call to main speakers, the audio deck will switch the output from the comm officer&#39;s headset to the main bridge speakers, and they will instantly be talking to everyone.</p>
<p>Or, the captain presses a button on his chair controls - &quot;Bridge to Engineering&quot;. Without hesitation, the bridge audio will be connected to Engineering, and the captain will be talking to Scotty, and vice versa. The possibilities are limitless.</p>
<p>Another challenge which was apparent was whether to do a passive or active speaker system. Passive is what most people think of when they hear about a sound system - all inputs route to an amplifier which then sends the powered signal to each of the speakers. However, for a ship with as many audio zones as we have, you would need at least 6 amps, which adds up quickly.</p>
<p>Instead, we opted for an active speaker system, one in which all of the speakers already have amplifiers inside of them - all you do is send signal directly to the speaker and it cranks it out for you. This way, instead of getting separate amps, we just send the signal straight from the audio deck to the speakers, cutting down on cost and complexity. Subwoofers will be placed underneath the raised floor of the bridge, allowing for sound to reverberate through the entire simulator.</p>
<p>Also, as I mentioned, headsets will be the way to go in this ship. There will still be a speaker and handheld microphones in the control room, but the flight director will also be able to use a personal headset, programmed to hear only what the flight director wants to hear and to speak only where the flight director wants to. This will provide additional flexibility to the flight director. </p>
<h2 id="cameras-and-video">Cameras and Video</h2>
<p>All camera and video data is being transmitted over Cat5e cable, simplifying the simulator extensively. The cameras are IP-PoE, which allows us to place them anywhere we want and access them from any computer. We also have talked about installing a new DVR and overhauling the entire schools camera system to run along side our cameras.</p>
<p> The video system is HDMI over Cat5e, mainly for simplifying our cable runs. Instead of using DVD players, this simulator will have its own dedicated video computer powered by Flint. Clips will be stored and then cued up based on which mission the simulator is doing. This also provides the flexibility for dynamic tactical cards -  since everything is connected to Flint, tactical cards which are pertinent to the situation can be displayed (shields, communications, etc.) Also, the cameras are linked in too, which means that the captain and engineer could have both an audio and video conversation. In fact, the Flight Director could even get in on the conversation too with some special technologies which we are currently developing.</p>
<h2 id="lighting-and-effects">Lighting and Effects</h2>
<p>DMX512 (Digital Multiplex) is the industry standard for theatrical lighting. It allows you 512 channels of lighting control, each channel with its own dimmer capable of being set to any value from 0% to 100% intensity. Magellan and Galileo use DMX lighting, both computer controlled.</p>
<p>Lighting in previous Space Center ships consisted of large panels of lighting controls with manual dimmers (for shaking the lights during explosions) and switches for changing between red lights and white lights (or blue, if you are the Phoenix). The lights themselves were incandescent can lights (or CFLs in the Magellan), tinted either blue or red for the accent lights. Some of the newer ships, such as the Odyssey II or some DSC ships, use RGB tape light, controlled via remote control. These tape lights have separate colors for red, green, and blue (combining them creates white light), and theoretically can produce any color of the spectrum. However, being remote controlled made them laggy and slow and limited the possibilities of color production. The lighting we chose was controlled by a DMX driver, meaning lighting changes are instantaneous, computer controlled, and each channel (red, green, and blue) and be set to any intensity individually, creating 16 million possibilities of color.</p>
<p>We opted for doing a system with RGB LED strip lights in addition to bright RGB PAR can fixtures to act as spotlights. Believe it or not, it&#39;s really difficult to find cans which have the certifications necessary to be installed in a permanent location. Through our perusals of the internet, we managed to find something which was similar to our tape lighting, but in a retrofit can structure - basically designed to take the place of a normal can fixture in a home. Go figure, though - it wasn&#39;t certified. </p>
<p>We continued our search until eventually we came across the mother-load; an RGBAW+UV PAR Can. Yep, you read that right: Red-Green-Blue-Amber-White+Ultra Violet. That&#39;s six different types of LEDs which fit into this thing. Not only that but they come in two sizes, are 100% computer controllable, super bright, and individually addressable. Oh, and best of all: they are CE certified. We&#39;re right now exploring what kinds of effects we can do with lights this beefy.</p>
<h2 id="effects-interaction">Effects &amp; Interaction</h2>
<p>Since the world has gone the direction of IoT (Internet of Things, or internet connected toasters), the capabilities of having human-computer interactive elements has gone through the roof. Our abilities for having real-time physical feedback for certain user interactions.</p>
<p>Take, for example, the brig. In the old Voyager, there was just an array of fluorescent blacklights, switched from the control room, indicating a force field. The security officers would have special sashes which allowed them to walk through the force field with anything they might have been carrying. To get though the field, you have to have a sash. However, the lights remained on whenever anyone stepped through them - there was no indication that the forcefield did anything.</p>
<p>In the new ship, we are going to be placing a Raspberry Pi microcomputer in the wall adjacent to the brig. Connected to it will be an RFID (Radio Frequency ID, or micro ID - they put these things in credit cards and your pets) reader and a camera. The RFID reader will be programmed to detect specific RFID which will be sewn into the two security sashes in the new security uniforms. To enter the brig, security will have to badge the scanner to deactivate the force field (since the brig lights are computer controlled, it will be totally automatic). A sound effect will play as the forcefield dims. They can then throw the bad guys in, badge again, and the force field will flicker back to life.</p>
<p>What if someone breaches the forcefield? Well, that&#39;s what the camera is for. It will be constantly scanning to see if there is someone or something in the way of the forcefield. If it notices something in the path, it sends a signal to the brig, which will play a sound effect and flicker, as if the force field was aggravated. That should be enough of an effect to keep someone from stepping through. </p>
<p>Engineering panels throughout the ship will also interface with the main computer systems in various ways. Power conduits which affect the lighting, a set of self-destruct buttons which must be pushed simultaneously to work properly, video conferencing; The point is that we can connect just about anything we want to the system and, with the right code in place, it will just work. </p>
<hr>
<p>So, that&#39;s the gist. Granted, all of this has come about after months of planning, tinkering, thinking things through, and discussing options, in addition to hours of research and development. This ship is going to be incredible, that&#39;s for sure. Stay tuned! There&#39;s more coming.
Cheers!</p>
]]></description><link>https://ralexanderson.com/posts/how-to-build-a-space-ship-part-2-the-plans/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ralexanderson.com/posts/how-to-build-a-space-ship-part-2-the-plans/</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Anderson]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2015 05:18:06 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Ferraris don't grow on trees]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://bryce.vc/post/122199637090/ferraris-dont-grow-on-trees">Give this one a good read.</a> It&#39;s a quick read, but shows how important, how valuable it is to do things for yourself. Nowadays, it&#39;s dead simple to get someone to do anything for you for a price. Is it worth it, even if you have the money? What are some of the unexpected consequences of putting your work onto someone else?</p>
<p>Cheers!</p>
]]></description><link>https://ralexanderson.com/posts/ferraris-dont-grow-on-trees/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ralexanderson.com/posts/ferraris-dont-grow-on-trees/</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Anderson]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2015 02:42:10 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Fathers]]></title><description><![CDATA[<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/R5FxdCgD-qI" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>

<p>This video gets me every time. I can&#39;t watch it without being filled to the brim with awe, inspiration, anticipation, excitement and joy. It shows, succinctly, two facets of my eternal identity:</p>
<ol>
<li>I am a son of an eternal God, a Man who prefers to be called Father. His greatest joy and His greatest purpose and His greatest fulfillment comes, in part, through me. His care and consideration for me is always apparent. The sacrifices which He has made and which He continues to make leave me breathless, especially the sacrifice of His Beloved Son. I know He is constantly listening to me and answers my prayers. His direction for my life is not always what I would choose for myself, but every time, without fail, when I follow His plan in faith, I find that it is always the right path. He loves me, and I love Him.</li>
<li>As a son of a God, I have divine potential to be a father, both in this life and in the life to come. I see my future self in the man in the video - providing for a family, both in physical needs through hard honest work and in spiritual needs through constant prayer and study; guiding and directing my family in partnership with both a righteous daughter of God and God himself; making a difference in the lives of my children by supporting their righteous desires and, let&#39;s be honest, getting a little rowdy sometimes. I&#39;m looking forward to all of that.
Happy Father&#39;s Day.</li>
</ol>
<p>Cheers!</p>
]]></description><link>https://ralexanderson.com/posts/fathers/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ralexanderson.com/posts/fathers/</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Anderson]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2015 02:41:13 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Dad]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>I&#39;ve <a href="http://ralexanderson.com/blog/spiritual-experiences-at-the-happiest-place-on-earth">written about my dad</a> on this blog before. I make it no secret that I truly look up to him and revere him, not only because he&#39;s my dad, but also because he stands as an exemplary human being. My dad is a good man. </p>
<p>My mom has told me many stories about how my dad compared to other guys she was dating when they first met. These other gents were incredibly exciting - boating trips, snow skiing, hiking, motorcycles. My dad on the other hand seemingly fit a different end of the spectrum - unassuming, friendly, but not as outstanding. In other words, normal. (Can I point out how many extraordinary people in our lives are really just normal people doing the best that they can? I totally relate to feeling like just a regular &#39;normal&#39; person - it doesn&#39;t mean anything about who you are or what kind of life you do/might lead.)</p>
<p>My mom went out on dates with him mainly because he was just such a nice guy. Friendly, funny (and, as I <a href="http://elitedaily.com/dating/why-the-funny-guy-beats-the-hot-guy-every-time/995281/">recently read</a>, there is much to be said for dating a funnyman), and (my mom always emphasized this part) kind. She could spend lots of time with him because she felt comfortable around him (and there is a lot to be said for that particular quality - people feeling comfortable around you). Over time, she realized that of all the people she was dating, my dad was the only one she really wanted to date.</p>
<p>My parents&#39; lives together haven&#39;t been perfect, and my dad isn&#39;t a perfect man. But he makes up for it in some wonderful and incredible ways.</p>
<ul>
<li>We didn&#39;t always have scripture study in our home every night, but we most certainly never missed family prayers and going to church every week.</li>
<li>For that matter, we struggled a lot with family home evening, but we never missed our weekly family movie night.</li>
<li>My dad is a strong-willed and passionately opinionated person and sometimes expresses his feelings about certain situations, even in the Church. Regardless, I never once remember him complaining about having a particular calling; I never remember him arguing directly with a leader. Instead, I remember him dutifully and diligently fulfilling all of his callings to the best of his ability; I remember his monthly home teaching excursions and being willing to give service at a moments notice.</li>
<li>He was always worthy to give a priesthood blessing. Not once, when asked, has he ever hesitated or said &#39;not this time&#39;. This is the man who, when he was younger, would walk to church all by himself so he could exercise his Aaronic Priesthood. He did not take his responsibility to be worthy lightly. </li>
<li>He is a hard worker and has always provided for our family. Never have we had want in our house. Only recently have I begun to realize just how difficult and how much of a sacrifice this had to have been for him. </li>
<li>Most importantly, I&#39;ve never doubted that my father loves me. Whether it be him taking me out to get a root beer freeze after a particularly painful orthodontic appointment or him coming to my plays or events, or even just having him around - I have always known that I am part of what makes his world good.</li>
</ul>
<p>So, thanks Dad, for being a great example to me. Thanks for showing me how to live my live in the best way possible. Thanks for not doing things easy, but instead doing them right. The impact and influence you have and will have on me is timeless and priceless to me!</p>
<p>Cheers!</p>
]]></description><link>https://ralexanderson.com/posts/dad/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ralexanderson.com/posts/dad/</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Anderson]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2015 02:39:05 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Brave]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/ralex93/blog/images/o2qgqCma7qoE2CYiw-undefined" alt="Mommy and Daddy"></p>
<p>My mother is the bravest woman I know.</p>
<p>I was born in a time of great uncertainty and challenge. Funds were short; expenses were high. I was kid number four, and another mouth to feed is never an easy thing. But my parents welcomed me into the world with open arms and loving hearts - it wasn&#39;t until I was much older that I realized how difficult of a time that was.</p>
<p>I&#39;ve never asked my mom if she has any regrets, but there&#39;s one thing she could say that wouldn&#39;t surprise me: &quot;I regret not being there.&quot; Her dream her entire life has been to be a mom, to stay home and raise her family. In a twist of irony, that has been a fleeting dream during much of her marriage. It was no different when I was born. She had to work several jobs in addition to my dad&#39;s income in order for them to collectively pay the mortgage and put food on the table. She was gone early in the morning, late at night, on holidays, on weekends. In short, all the time.</p>
<p>Still, she read to me and sang to me and prayed with me and tucked me in every night. She may not remember, but I do.</p>
<p>She&#39;s always been more concerned about the needs of others over herself. The fact that she wasn&#39;t always home when I was younger is a testament to me of just how much she loves me; not because she denied herself from me, but because she denied herself a dream for me.</p>
<p>She may never see the tangible effect she’s had on my family&#39;s lives. She may not remember or consider those small, quiet, short, seemingly insignificant moments which she had with each of us. But I can guarantee that each of her children (and her husband, for that matter) have many memories of seemingly inconsequential moments with untold effects.</p>
<p>Thanks mommy.</p>
<p>Cheers.</p>
]]></description><link>https://ralexanderson.com/posts/brave/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ralexanderson.com/posts/brave/</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Anderson]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 10 May 2015 02:35:20 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Alone]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.kow.fm/we-need-time-alone-to-think/">I found this beauty of prose</a> and immediately related. That is to say, it not only resonated with me, but also answered some deep, poignant questions I&#39;ve had for a few weeks.</p>
<p>The author (possibly a Mormon - he hails from SLC) usually blogs about programming and fighting with code compilers. This time, though, he directs his comments mostly in condemnation of social media and internet time-wasting. I&#39;ve written similar sentiments. &quot;You&#39;ll never know how much of your time is being stolen by the internet...&quot; he says. It took an incredibly intimate moment, and possibly a little bit of divine intervention, for him to see through the fog, ignore the voices saying &quot;Twitter is calling!&quot; and notice those things which are most important, paradoxically close yet distant: his family and himself.</p>
<p>When I say himself (and when I say himself, please, dear reader, relate him to yourself), I don&#39;t mean to say that I perceive him to be self-centered. Just the opposite in fact (again, paradoxically). When he was playing games on his phone or reading some meme or watching some video on the internet, that is when he was most selfish, thinking only of instant gratification which comes from quick hits of dopamine after one more &#39;Achievement Unlocked!&#39; No, in this case, he wasn&#39;t thinking of gratifying himself at all. All he was thinking about was improvement. &quot;I recognized what I had been doing wrong and worked out ways to do better. I just required a few quiet moments with myself.&quot;</p>
<p>I honestly have very little to add to what he said. The succinctness and thoughtfulness caught me off guard and made me realize that I was in the same trap he was. But it also reminded me how easy it is to get out of that trap.</p>
<p>I think I&#39;ll be making some changes come May 1st.</p>
<p>Cheers!</p>
]]></description><link>https://ralexanderson.com/posts/alone/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ralexanderson.com/posts/alone/</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Anderson]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2015 02:33:23 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[How's your Heart?]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/ralex93/blog/images/4JGj9uG6qKqNRJxRM-undefined" alt="Where are you headed?"></p>
<p>One of my favorite scriptures in the entire standard works is found in the Book of Mormon, Helaman 3:35:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Nevertheless they did fast and pray oft, and did wax stronger and stronger in their humility, and firmer and firmer in the faith of Christ, unto the filling their souls with joy and consolation, yea, even to the purifying and the sanctification of their hearts, which sanctification cometh because of their yielding their hearts unto God.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This scripture has been an anchor for me. It has shown me how I can gain answers to prayer and find remission of my sins; it has helped me to focus on the things that bring true happiness; it has guided my decisions and helped me to realize whether I was yielding my heart to God, or setting my heart on the vain things of the world; it has helped me to know how I was doing, a &#39;standard&#39; of conversion and devotion to God.</p>
<p>I&#39;m sure that these individuals still sinned. I&#39;m sure they still screwed up all the time. But I am also certain that they frequently applied repentance. I&#39;m certain they studied their scriptures. I&#39;m certain that when they fasted and prayed, it wasn&#39;t focused on what they wanted but instead sought to know the will of God and how they could fulfill it. That line about &quot;yielding their hearts unto God&quot; is the entire crux of the verse - by directing our hearts and wills to God, our actions follow. It is that yielding which makes our humility wax stronger and our faith wax firmer. In short, conversion.</p>
<p>This verse serves as a beautiful, yet stark contrast to the preceding two verses, in which the author laments:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>33 And in the fifty and first year of the reign of the judges there was peace also, save it were the pride which began to enter into the church--not into the church of God, but into the hearts of the people who professed to belong to the church of God--
34 And they were lifted up in pride, even to the persecution of many of their brethren. Now this was a great evil, which did cause the more humble part of the people to suffer great persecutions, and to wade through much affliction.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This scripture refers to individuals who fit into a unique category: those who might be listed on the records of the church and even attend church meetings and fulfil callings, yet are not part of the <a href="https://www.lds.org/scriptures/nt/rom/12.5?lang=eng#4">body of Christ</a>. There is something about them which caused them to dissent from the church - not a physical dissension (yet), but a spiritual dissension. Perhaps they became enveloped in the darkness of sin; perhaps their pride began to <a href="https://www.lds.org/scriptures/bofm/jacob/4.14?lang=eng#13">cloud their vision</a>. Their testimony didn&#39;t hold, and, slowly, imperceptibly, they lost their conversion. However, instead of outright leaving the church, they continued to go through the motions, performing duties, speaking in church, saying prayers, etc. They, possibly, <a href="https://www.lds.org/scriptures/ot/isa/29.13?lang=eng#12">draw near to the Savior with their lips, but their <em>hearts</em> are far from Him</a>.</p>
<p>Perhaps there were things about church policy which they didn&#39;t agree with. Perhaps they were disappointed with a decision made by the leadership of the church. Or, on the other side of the coin, perhaps they themselves persecuted those who had honest questions about they church. Perhaps they judged others to be sinners, when all those &#39;sinners&#39; wanted were honest answers and a desire to learn the truth.</p>
<p>Or perhaps it was none of those things, and I just made them up. Actually, I bring those things up because they seem to be a <a href="http://www.kutv.com/news/features/local-news/stories/BYU-students-speak-out-against-Honor-Code-policies-to-national-accreditation-board-115784.shtml#.VTR1bc7qdSV">common</a> <a href="http://www.kutv.com/news/features/local-news/stories/Vocal-oppositions-at-LDS-General-Conference-not-a-first-111230.shtml#.VTR2xs7qdSU">theme</a> in the church nowadays, on both ends of the spectrum: both those who raise concerns about the church, and many of those who react to those raising concerns. Those who speak out against the church today do so for many reasons. Some of the groups are incredibly civil and kind about their disaffection; some are sharp and cruel, openly opposing or demeaning the leaders of this church who they oppose.</p>
<p>The same thing can be said for &quot;active members&quot; who are defamatory against those who publicly raise questions about the church. In the <a href="http://gephardtdaily.com/local/byu-asst-coach-takes-heat-over-tweet-after-lds-general-conference-t/">heat</a> of defending the church, the Saviors injunction to &quot;Love your enemies, bless them that curse you, do good to them that hate you, and pray for them which despitefully use you, and persecute you&quot; is forgotten. </p>
<p>It would be a poor move on my part to discuss these &#39;dissenting&#39; members in any detail on this blog. Their concerns are broad and diverse and contain a multitude of layers. I am probably poorly informed and ill-equipped to provide any constructive addition to the discussions which have already been happening on the internet. </p>
<p>One thing that I will say, and that I hope has been apparent in this blog post, is that constructive discussion is healthy. If someone perceives a problem, bringing it up through the proper channels is the right thing to do. Asking questions is not a sin in this church. (On the contrary, asking questions is what brought about this church in the first place!) </p>
<hr>
<p>With the release of several <a href="http://ldsessays.com/">essays</a> by the Church regarding more controversial topics of doctrine and history, many members have had more questions than ever. And that&#39;s okay. The church has always provided avenues for members to have these questions addressed. (Namely, Priesthood and auxiliary leaders, culminating with the Bishop and Stake President). The one caveat is that the member realize that this church is not changeable by popular vote. Policy won&#39;t be altered just because it&#39;s the &#39;in&#39; thing to do. It might be disappointing to some, but often, in many cases, the answer will be a firm &#39;No&#39;, or &#39;The Lord has not revealed anything on the matter (implying the leader has no intention of speculating)&#39;, or &#39;I can see why you feel that way, but there is nothing I can do.&#39; </p>
<p>It can be difficult to have something which you strongly believe challenged by someone placed in authority over you. It takes a lot of humility to not take it personally. Then again, that&#39;s the whole point of this post, isn&#39;t it? Pride is the defining influence which in turn leads to dissension. If one is not already humble, then avenues like the Bishop and Stake President won&#39;t really make much difference.</p>
<p> Of course, those avenues are Church-sponsored. When I say that, I mean that there is an avenue which is completely outside of church jurisdiction and available to anyone.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>They did fast and pray oft and did wax stronger and stronger in their humility...</p>
</blockquote>
<p>There were many times on my mission when I had questions. There were times when the opposition was incredibly convincing. There were times when all I had to hold on to was prayer.</p>
<p>I can remember one specific occasion when I felt like everything I was doing was a waste. I wasn&#39;t sure about anything. The only thing I knew was real was God. So I talked to him. &quot;God,&quot; I said, &quot;Here I am. I&#39;m a missionary. and I want to be a great missionary. But I can&#39;t do that without knowing that the Book of Mormon is true.&quot; Boom. As soon as that thought escaped my mind and went to the heavens, I felt the most incredible peace. It was a peace I had felt before, a peace with a strange certainty of meaning and direction. This time, that peace told me &quot;It&#39;s true. You know it&#39;s true. You&#39;ve always known it&#39;s true.&quot;</p>
<p>That experience held me through my whole mission. It reminded me of a story of a young Asian, returning home to his family after finding the Church. He would be exiled, scorned, and persecuted. But his faithful response was <a href="https://www.lds.org/general-conference/2007/04/its-true-isn-t-it-then-what-else-matters?lang=eng">&quot;It&#39;s true, isn&#39;t it? Then what else matters?&quot;</a></p>
<p>This time that we live in has been prophesied about by ancient and modern prophets. Good and evil are polarizing, but it&#39;s not just happening in the world; it&#39;s happening in the Church too. <a href="https://www.lds.org/scriptures/nt/matt/24.24?lang=eng">&quot;They shall deceive the very elect.&quot;</a></p>
<p>That being said, we have to be careful, not only of those who teach against the leaders and teachings of the church, but also those who overzealously defend the church. Yes, we need to unwaveringly  stand for the right, but we don&#39;t need to be proverbially chopping off ears like <a href="https://www.lds.org/scriptures/nt/john/18.10?lang=eng">Peter did</a>.</p>
<p>A reminder: sanctification comes through yielding your heart unto God, not men, no matter what their opinion, position, or calling is. Fasting and prayer can lead to greater humility and greater faith.</p>
<p>Cheers.</p>
]]></description><link>https://ralexanderson.com/posts/hows-your-heart/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ralexanderson.com/posts/hows-your-heart/</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Anderson]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2015 02:28:07 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[#becauseHeLIves]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/ralex93/blog/images/H8hSfvfCJz7MWr56m-undefined" alt="The In Between"></p>
<p>That&#39;s my favorite scene from this year&#39;s <a href="http://mormon.org">Mormon.org</a> Easter video. I would totally recommend the whole thing, but this scene really spoke out to me. </p>
<p>Just a few moments before this, with the caption of &quot;During the bad,&quot; it showed an elderly man lying on his death bed, a person next to him with downturned head. That hit close to home for me. My father is currently in a struggle with cancer and has been for the past 10 years. It&#39;s more aggressive now than ever, and I don&#39;t know how long I will have him. Naturally, when I saw that scene, in my mind I saw my father.</p>
<p>To then jump from that to &quot;The In-Between,&quot; where a girl finds solace in her tub of expensive ice cream. I laughed out loud when I saw it! Comedy is all about timing and surprises, and this one totally shocked me. After such a heavy scene (especially for me), this light-hearted pity party was totally hysterical. What caused her to be in such great duress to the point that she felt perfectly fine downing two pints of ice cream single-handedly? Was school too much for her? She&#39;s dressed up nice - maybe she just got back from a bad job interview. Or perhaps her date for the evening stood her up. Regardless, here she is munching away at her sugary treat with the intent that it will make her feel better.</p>
<p>I thought to myself &quot;This is so high school-like. That ice cream isn&#39;t going to solve anything (although, truth be told, I&#39;ve downed my fair share in desperation). Whatever problem she&#39;s going through is totally temporary - she&#39;ll forget about it in a week.&quot;
And then I came back to myself, thinking of my dad and &quot;The Bad&quot; times. But as I pondered, my own words came back to me: &quot;It&#39;s totally temporary.&quot; And it is. </p>
<p>Yeah, it&#39;s not &quot;I&#39;ll get over it in a week&quot; kind of temporary - the thought of my dad passing hurts now, and it&#39;s going to hurt even worse when he&#39;s gone. It could hurt for the rest of my life. But it&#39;s still temporary. Death is temporary. Resurrection is real. Families are forever. Because of Him.</p>
<p>The video ends with a captioned montage: &quot;He is here. No matter who you are or who you were, He is here. No exceptions. No lost causes. At all times, in all places. He is here.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;He rose on the third day. He lives today. Find Him.&quot;</p>
<p>#BecauseHeLives</p>
<p>Cheers!</p>
<div class="embed-responsive embed-responsive-16by9">
  <iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/BZqTRSVA1YA" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</div>]]></description><link>https://ralexanderson.com/posts/becausehelives/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ralexanderson.com/posts/becausehelives/</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Anderson]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2015 02:23:56 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[How to Build A Space Ship Part 1 - The Background]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>I make it no secret that I have a strange hobby. People are always either impressed, surprised, or confused when I describe to them what I enjoy doing in my spare time. It&#39;s not like it&#39;s that different from other hobbies which people have; some people make models of trains; some people made digital models of real-life systems. </p>
<p>I am making a futuristic starship simulator. </p>
<p>I mean make in a very loose sense. This is hardly my project, and I am hardly a contributor at all. But the small part I am playing is certainly an integral role in the process. So far, I&#39;ve had a say in the software controls, the universe which the simulator will operate in, the lighting and sound system layout of the simulator set, and some of the custom hardware integration which we will be using.</p>
<p>I might be getting ahead of myself, though. I suppose I had better take a step back and explain the whole process from top to bottom. </p>
<p><img src="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/ralex93/blog/images/jbSkywHtL4NEh82vq-undefined" alt="Victor Williamson, AKA Bossman"></p>
<p>This is Victor Williamson. Inspired by Star Trek, and seeing the benefits of simulated education early on in his career, he pioneered the concept of using science fiction simulations to teach Science, Technology, Engineering, and Math (STEM). Early on, he would do simple role-plays where his students would push paper buttons on cardboard boxes and he would react by narrating a story using his vast collection of false accents and an overhead projector. His first flights were recon missions to Mars where they would skim the surface, talking about the nature of the Red Planet. Students were interested, but not really excited. So he figured he would spice things up.</p>
<p>He had a Romulan ship attack them.</p>
<p>It worked. By adding in that bit of drama, the kids were suddenly glued to their chairs, their minds fixed on the simulation. He would go on to craft &#39;missions&#39; like this one which revolved around a main story point, but also featured a prominent science topic: negotiating with the Romulans to go and study a Supernova; passing by a black hole and dealing with the relativistic effects; deciding what to do with an escaped slave who emerged from a wormhole. Adding the artistic elements (turning STEM to STEAM) helped to round out the missions and keep the kids interested. Lots of good fortune and several thousand dollars of grant money later, and a permanent simulator was built in his school&#39;s back lot.</p>
<p>And thus the Space Center was born.</p>
<p><img src="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/ralex93/blog/images/osAdvD85N4oqBqPMn-undefined" alt="The original Voyager"></p>
<p>The Voyager was built in 1990, the first of six ships built at Central School (the last of which was built in 2005). The image above is how the flagship looked shortly before it was shut down in 2012. For 22 years, this ship was the stage of space dramas teaching school kids teamwork, leadership, math, science, communication, responsibility, and decision making. It was a classroom, laboratory, and summer camp destination. </p>
<p>While the Voyager was open, the Space Center was also the central hub of a bustling volunteer organization. Hundreds of students impressed and inspired by the field trip experience on one of these ships would become even more involved. I was one of them.</p>
<p>I was so fascinated with the experience of the Space Center that I made no delay in beginning my work as a volunteer. I had come to the Space Center many times with my older brother, who was already a volunteer, and was blown away at what happened behind the scenes that I knew I had to become part of it. </p>
<p>I put in my volunteer registration papers in 2006, and began the process of observing and volunteering. I saw the control rooms, the skilled Flight Directors in charge of the flights (and which I always wanted to become), the supervisors assisting and monitoring the crews, the volunteers performing acting parts and running computer stations. </p>
<p>My brother, Brent, was a programmer, so naturally I would join with them. These programmers would meet at least weekly to work on the next cool computer terminal or software controlled gadget. The  meetings were truly amazing. None of the members of this &#39;Programming Guild&#39; were even out of high school, and yet every week there would be some new, amazing idea for something to put into a simulator. An integrated video system for creating video playlists for the missions; a fluid set of controls, which would allow you to put any screen on any computer; a sound effects player which integrated into the controls to react to what the kids were doing; a push server architecture. Some of these things would be discussed, even prototypes made. But none of us were skilled enough to be able to build it all. Over time, the programmers moved on to bigger and better things, leaving me as the lone remnant of that guild.</p>
<p>I eventually did reach my dream of becoming a Flight Director, and found it to be one of the most fulfilling and powerful experiences of my life up to that point. As Flight Director, I was in charge of representing the Space Center to the students who came. I would brief them on their mission, train them  on how to use the simulator, launch them into space, play the role of all the aliens they came in contact with, play the mood music and sound effects and video and tactical view screens and interact with their computer stations and direct my volunteers and actors to do the various things which they needed to do... it was a lot of work. But in addition to doing all those things to put on a good show, I tried my best to remember that this was an educational venture (or EdVenture as we like to call it), so I mixed in the science, math, and social studies as much as possible. </p>
<p>I also became a full-fledged programmer, and started working on creating new simulator controls. One by one, I re-programmed each of the Space Center simulators (excepting the Voyager) using the new Revolution programming environment. Many of the ideas which were first brought up in the programming meetings were implemented in these controls. Truth be told, though, they were buggy and not entirely functional. There was so much more that they could be, given time, resources, and experience.</p>
<p>When the former Set Director, or simulator manager, of the ship I ran left on a mission to Korea, I was placed in charge. Suddenly I was responsible for an entire starship simulator. In the weeks following, me and my co-director Bracken Funk did some major modifications and renovations to the ship. I tore that ship apart and put it back together, learning how it worked. </p>
<p><img src="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/ralex93/blog/images/Eh8CT3Bdn6BhDSAq6-undefined" alt="At least I didn&#39;t look like this guy"></p>
<p>I learned how the networking ran through conduit, and I even pulled my own cables through to set up a phone in the front of the ship. I learned how the audio inputs fed into the mixer, which fed into the amp which ran out to all the speakers, and I even added a few more speakers to the mix. I learned how the video systems converged to two switcher boxes, and the output of those ran to the main view screens on the ship, and then, out of necessity, learned how to set up a RGB Component video system (it had a funny glitch, though, where the signal would cut out whenever you switched inputs, returning after a few seconds of blackness). I did some custom electrical wiring to create a smoke machine timer, a transporter light, and a strobe light spark effect. This little ship pushed the boundaries of what kinds of effects we could pull in simulators.</p>
<p>Also, working off of the groundwork laid by my brother, I installed a DMX (computer controlled) lighting system in the Galileo simulator. This allowed the lights to be turned on, off, switched from red to white, and shaken (during an explosion) with the mere push of a button. This was an exciting time.</p>
<p>I left the Space Center officially in August of 2011 when I moved to Provo to attend BYU. I knew that I wouldn&#39;t have the means necessary to be coming to and from the Space Center to program and fix bugs, and I needed to let my successor get his feet wet without me hovering behind him. I left on my mission in January of 2012.</p>
<p>August of 2012 brought the closure of the Space Center by the Alpine School District for renovations. By October, there was no sign of the Space Center ever re-opening and a political campaign was founded to fight the District&#39;s decision and bring the Space Center back. This campaign was successful to an extent. In time, the District caved and began to perform the necessary remodeling. However, the original Voyager simulator (by far the most impressive and attractive of the five) was deemed too much of a hazard to be retrofitted, and was closed permanently. </p>
<p>I got the chance to see the Voyager after I got home from my mission. It was hardly a shell of it&#39;s former glory. Dust was everywhere; random implements were strewn all over the place. The desks, void of computers, revealed the plywood which was concealed within. I remembered going up those spiral stairs, exploring the Captain&#39;s loft, working from the Engineering platform or sleeping in the bunks on Deck 2. Now all of those things were either gone or boarded up. Nothing was left except memories.</p>
<p>During this time, Victor, who had been director of the Space Center from when it opened to when it closed, moved from Central to another elementary school, and eventually retired completely. Not too long afterward, though, he was approached by Renaissance Academy, a charter school in northern Utah County, and asked if he wanted to make a space simulator for that school. He accepted. </p>
<p>Since then, a group of Space Center volunteer alumni have joined together to create what we call the Farpoint Creative Team. This team is a band of some of the Space Center&#39;s skilled and talented volunteers who have gone on to get degrees and training. Helping to construct this new simulator is our way of giving back. </p>
<p>It&#39;s remarkable who we have on the team. Of course, Victor is the visionary leader and chief educator. We also have science fiction and astronomy experts; a data analyst, graphic designer, and expert flight director; an architect; an engineer; medical professionals; and programmers (my brother and myself). All of us bring something unique to the table, and all of us together, pooling our resources, think we&#39;ll be able to make the most impressive, most immersive experience ever. Not only that, but also an environment where learning will happen organically. </p>
<p>There was a little bit of debate about what we were going to call the new ship. Vanguard was a name that was sticking for a time. However, much to the approval of the team as a whole, we decided on something better.</p>
<p>The new ship will be called Voyager.</p>
<p><img src="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/ralex93/blog/images/z3muFhcPayDSBoX6M-undefined" alt="SPACESHIP"></p>
<p>Cheers!</p>
]]></description><link>https://ralexanderson.com/posts/how-to-build-a-space-ship-part-1-the-background/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ralexanderson.com/posts/how-to-build-a-space-ship-part-1-the-background/</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Anderson]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2015 01:25:52 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Nice]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>I was going on a date with someone I didn&#39;t know. </p>
<p>It really wasn&#39;t that big of a deal. I had surprised myself by asking her for her number out of the blue and, sure enough, she gave it to me. I called her later on that week to set up a casual lunch date.</p>
<p>When I told a friend of mine, she naturally wanted to know all about this girl I was taking out.</p>
<p>&quot;Well,&quot; I responded, not really knowing what to say, &quot;she&#39;s nice.&quot;</p>
<p>My friend scoffed and replied &quot;Around here, just about everybody is nice.&quot;</p>
<p>That totally struck me. Living in the heart of Provo, surrounded by a bunch of Mormon college students, of course everybody is nice. </p>
<p>But that wasn&#39;t the point my friend was trying to make. She really was saying, &quot;Okay, that&#39;s great. But, come on, tell me something I don&#39;t know. What makes this girl any different than any other girl? What makes her truly special?&quot; </p>
<p>I&#39;ve been pondering that ever since.</p>
<hr>
<p><a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2015/01/11/fashion/modern-love-to-fall-in-love-with-anyone-do-this.html?_r=0">This article</a> made headlines a couple of weeks ago. A scientific way to fall in love with anyone. Answer a bunch of questions and then stare at each other. It takes an hour. According to this, you can seriously fall in love with someone in 60 minutes. It doesn&#39;t matter who the person is. It could be a friend, a lover, or a complete stranger. It doesn&#39;t matter. If you follow all the steps, you&#39;ll fall in love. Period. </p>
<p>But how does it work? You ask tough questions, questions that tap into a place people don&#39;t express as much. You learn about others on a deeper level, because they drop their barriers and become vulnerable. You begin to see, to understand. You finish off the questions with a gaze into the eyes of your partner, through the windows of the soul. You see that person at their most vulnerable - they&#39;ve shared with you things they haven&#39;t shared with another human being; you look into their eyes longer than anyone has ever looked before. You realize that what is before you, what you&#39;ve been interacting with isn&#39;t merely an object with a voice. It&#39;s a person. And, suddenly, you love them.</p>
<p>An excellent example of this is The Story Trek, a BYUTV show which asks average people a simple question: &quot;What&#39;s your story?&quot; Every episode is unscripted, and every story told is aired. Every person has a story, and it&#39;s amazing just how quickly you can come to love a person simply after hearing it.</p>
<p>I saw this all the time as a missionary. We would run around, trying to talk to anyone willing to listen. They could be the most obscure, uninteresting person imaginable, and yet, once we got talking to them, we would find out there was so much more to them than what met the eye. As missionaries, we would immediately talk about things which are generally off-limits in conversation - Who is God? What is Salvation? What is truth, and how can you find it? And when people start talking about these things, walls go down. You begin to see inside their souls. You start to love them.</p>
<p>This Valentine&#39;s Day, I hope you&#39;ll be able to find a connection and <a href="http://lifehacker.com/how-to-move-past-the-superficial-and-build-deeper-frien-1685595122">deepen all friendships</a>. This isn&#39;t a holiday only about romantic couples-love (although there is nothing wrong with that). It&#39;s about the sincere expression of any kind of love, be it smitten 2nd graders making giant valentines to give to their crushes, to old friends reuniting after years apart. It&#39;s about reaching outside yourself, opening yourself to others in the hope that they will reciprocate. </p>
<p>It&#39;s a difficult thing to do. Being open requires vulnerability, which is expensive. I know many people who have been burned in the past to the point that they won&#39;t let just anyone in. Yet, ofttimes, these people need that human connection the most.</p>
<p>Yes, you can be nice to the person. You can say hi, give things to them, talk to them, whatever. But that only goes so far. Sometimes, you have to be the one to risk being vulnerable in order to make a connection with someone.  It requires truly empathizing, sacrificing, sharing their burden and pain, when necessary. It takes making that person a priority. </p>
<p>It&#39;s impossible to do this for every person you know. And that&#39;s okay. I know of only one Person who could genuinely show this much love so freely to so many. And, in the end, the best thing we can do is try our hardest to follow His example.</p>
<p>Don&#39;t just be nice.</p>
<p>Cheers!</p>
]]></description><link>https://ralexanderson.com/posts/nice/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ralexanderson.com/posts/nice/</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Anderson]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2015 01:24:28 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Two-thousand and Fourteen]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>It has been three years to the day that I left Utah to go to...Utah. Well, Utah, and then Pennsylvania. I went from civilian life to a life of service. I went from trust to testimony. I spent two years doing some of the most difficult, most frustrating, most challenging, most changing, and, ultimately, most rewarding things which I have ever done in my entire life.</p>
<p>One year ago, I came home, swapped the white shirts for tees and the slacks for jeans. After doing so much so differently for so long, what did I do with myself when I came home?</p>
<ul>
<li>For personal reasons, I decided to stay in my home ward instead of going to the local singles ward. I got a calling as a young mens advisor, teaching Priesthood twice a month and doing my darndest to be a good example to those boys.</li>
<li>I promptly returned to the Space Center in Pleasant Grove, working the daytime field trips in an effort to inspire elementary school kids not only to seek education in math, science and technology, but also to inspire self-confidence and teamwork. I wanted them to feel like what they did made a difference, and that they could do difficult things on their own.</li>
<li>Family matters prompted a spontaneous trip to Disneyland!</li>
<li>Thanks to my brother, I got hooked up with a sweet job at BlenderBottle in the IT department. As <a href="http://alex.andersonclan.org/blog/care">I have mentioned before</a>, this has been a blessing in so many ways, and a great opportunity to share the gospel.</li>
<li>I got involved with the Space Edventures Foundation&#39;s Farpoint Creative Team. Basically, it&#39;s a team of the Space Center&#39;s finest throughout the years. Our goal is to develop a simulator, controls, a universe, and curriculum to enhance the Space Center&#39;s methods of education. </li>
<li>This involvement included me breaking a vow to never write a single line of code again. Now, together with my brother, I&#39;ve started a company specifically for creating custom websites for clients. I&#39;ve also become interested in making a career out of it.</li>
<li>I went back to school during the Spring Semester at BYU. It was then that I decided to change my major to Pre-Graphic Design, in the hopes that I would be able to improve my skills for my work with Front-end development.</li>
<li>I spent the summer running summer camps and teaching programming classes for an American Fork company called Simply Coding.</li>
<li>I programmed a Design Your Own BlenderBottle web app which was used for a marketing campaign in June. You could customize your bottle with different colors, images, logos, and text and enter it into a contest. The winning bottles were actually made and sold for a limited time.</li>
<li>After not being there to see them leave, I was able to be there to see my amazing friends come home from their missions, one by one. It is a truly humbling thing to know that all of the people I surrounded myself with in high school and college were eager to give up part of their lives to serve their Father in Heaven.</li>
<li>After intensive prayer and one too many times of being asked to substitute teach Primary in my home ward, I decided it was time to move out. I packed my things and found myself rooming with my brother down in Provo.</li>
<li>The very first day I moved into my apartment, I got a calling - Activities committee co-chair. It has been vastly rewarding to be in a position where I get to scramble around in the weeks and days before an activity, trying to put something together that will be both fun and uplifting, only to see the pieces miraculously fall into place. I consider each and every successful activity to be a tender mercy of the Lord.</li>
<li>I started school again, focusing on the pre-requisites for Graphic Design. * Suddenly, I realized that I was an art student. This was a very puzzling, concerning thing. Nothing against art students, of course; I just never imagined myself being one of those people who carted around a drawing board and 50 different kinds of art utensils. </li>
<li>I got a girlfriend, and it was really great while it lasted. It taught me a lot about people, relationships, trust, honesty, and love. I can say I have no regrets. It was a time of my life which I am certain I will always remember. </li>
<li>I applied for the Graphic Design program, hoping for the best. A few weeks later I learned that I was not accepted. As I contemplated, I wondered if it was really what I wanted, if I was willing to <a href="http://markmanson.net/question">struggle</a> for that Graphic Design degree. I haven&#39;t come up with an answer yet.</li>
<li>Following finals, I spent a wonderful two weeks with my parents and sister and had a delightful Christmas and New Years. </li>
<li>I went back to school, taking some pre-requisites for Information Systems and Engineering. This is a guy who doesn&#39;t know what he wants to be when he grows up. ¯_(ツ)_/¯</li>
</ul>
<p>So there you have it. That is my year in a nut shell. I can&#39;t say that I did as much as the <a href="http://pittsburghmissionmemoirs.blogspot.com/">two years before it</a>, but I think I have done well with what the Lord has given me. Here&#39;s to another year!
Cheers!</p>
<hr>
<p>I actually had a cool opportunity to do some member missionary work at BlenderBottle. I was doing some wiring on a conference room table, and the electrician was obviously a guy with a story. He always wore a black hoodie and beanie, he had earrings in both ears. He just seemed like he had seen some life. He knew that I was fairly new at BlenderBottle, so he asked me about what I did before. I told him about my mission, to which he responded, &quot;I never went on a mission.&quot; As it turns out, earlier in his life he had some unfortunate interactions with some ward members which pushed him away. At this point in his life, though, he realized that he needed to make some changes; you see, he was now a dad and he realized that his kid needed good influence in order to make it in this world. I told him to read the Book of Mormon and get in touch with the missionaries - they would know how to help him teach his kid the right things. I don&#39;t know what became of him, but I hope I had a good influence on him.</p>
]]></description><link>https://ralexanderson.com/posts/two-thousand-and-fourteen/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ralexanderson.com/posts/two-thousand-and-fourteen/</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Anderson]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2015 01:19:57 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>